Finding aid for the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive Collection of Audio Materials, 1970-1999 LSC.2230
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Women Writers Read Their Work, 1976-1986; Series 15.; 37 audio cassette tapes
  - Wanda Coleman & Michelle Cliff, 1 April 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 2, Item 12)
    Recording of Wanda Coleman and Michelle Cliff reading their work at the Social and Public Art Resource Center (SPARC), in Venice, CA, in conjunction with the Women's Building in Los Angeles, CA. Founded in 1976, SPARC is an arts center that produces, preserves and conducts educational programs about community based public art works. The Women's Building was founded in 1973 by a group of women artists who were motivated by the feminist movement and lesbian activism. Wanda Coleman is an African American poet who grew up in the Watts neighborhood of Los Angeles. Coleman reads from her previously published and upcoming books of poetry. Michelle Cliff is a novelist and poet, born in Jamaica, whose work focuses on issues of race, class, and sexuality.
  - Laurel Ann Bogen: Interviewed by Eloise Klein Healy, 15 October 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 2, Item 13)
    A recording of a Women's Words episode on KPFK 90.7 Los Angeles, with host Eloise Klein Healy and guest Laurel Ann Bogen. The two writer discuss music, writing, poetry, and the process of getting books published. Bogen is a poet, teacher, and performance artist living in Los Angeles, CA.
  - Alice Bloch & Deena Metzger: Women Writers Series, 7 May 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 2, Item 14)
    Alice Bloch and Deena Metzger read selected written works for the Women Writers Series, organized by the Women's Building in Los Angeles, CA. Bloch is a Jewish lesbian writer, teacher, and has written two novels and an anthology of poetry. Metzger was the founder of the writing program at the Women's Building, is a writer, poet, and teacher.
  - Margaret Atwood, 7 May 1978; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 2, Item 15)
    Margaret Eleanor Atwood reads selected poetry at the Women's Building in Los Angeles, CA. Atwood was born on November 18, 1939 and is a Canadian poet, novelist, literary critic, and environmental activist. She is also a founder of the Writers' Trust of Canada, a non-profit literary organization that seeks to encourage Canada's writing community.
    Audio is difficult to understand at the beginning, with scratchiness and street sounds, but becomes clearer after minute 4.
  - Susan Anderson, 30 October 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 2, Item 16)
    Susan Anderson reads her selections of her writing.
    Audio on Side 1 only.
  - Paula Gunn Allen: Literary Salon, [ca. 1980s]; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 2, Item 17-18)
    Paula Gunn Allen discusses American Indian women, spirituality, and her professional life. She reads her and other writers' poems and provides analysis. Gunn Allen was a Native American poet, literary critic, lesbian activist, and novelist. She edited four collections of Native American traditional stories and contemporary works, and wrote two biographies of Native American women
  - Mitsuye Yamada and Nellie Wong: Women Writers Series, 21 May 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 1)
    Mitsuye Yamada and Nellie Wong read selections from their work at the Women's Building in Los Angeles, CA. They also discuss inspiration behind the work they read. Nellie Wong is a Chinese American, born in Oakland, CA, and is a poet and activist for feminist and socialist causes. Yamada is a Japanese American activist, feminist, essayist, poet, story writer, editor, and former professor of English.
  - Mitsuye Yamada, Terryl Hunter, & Gaila Turner: Sisterhood Bookstore Mininarathon, 1 November 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 2)
    Mitsuye Yamada, Terryl Hunter, Gaila Turner read selections from their work at Sisterhoof Bookstore in Los Angeles, CA.
  - Nellie Wong and Mitsuye Yamada: 9th Annual Women Writers Series, 21 November 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 3)
    Mitsuye Yamada and Nellie Wong read selections from their work at the Women's Building in Los Angeles, CA. Asian Pacific Women's Network co-sponsored the evening of readings by Asian American writers. They also discuss inspiration behind the work they read. Nellie Wong is a Chinese American, born in Oakland, CA, and is a poet and activist for feminist and socialist causes. Yamada is a Japanese American activist, feminist, essayist, poet, story writer, editor, and former professor of English. Note: Audio on Side 1 only.
    Audio on Side 1 only
  - Terry Wolverton and M.T. Hughes: Anti-Racism International, [ca. 1980s]; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 4)
    KPFK 90.7 FM Los Angeles radio program discussing anti-racism, with guest Terry Wolverton. They take calls from the public and discuss anti-racism efforts at organizations across Los Angeles, including at the Social and Public Art Resource Center in Venice, CA. Terry Wolverton was born in 1954 and is an American novelist, memoirist, poet, and editor. Her published works include, Insurgent Muse: Life and Art at the Woman's Building, The Labrys Reunion, and Embers.
  - Anne Sexton Reads, [ca. 1970s]; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 5)
    Anne Sexton reads her selections of her work. Sexton (1928-1974) was an American poet from Massachusetts. Her highly confessional prose includes themes of depression, her suicidal tendencies, and her relationships with her husband and children.
  - Jane Rule: Interviewed by Eloise Klein Healy, 26 February 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 6)
    Jane Rule is interviewed on KPFK 90.7, Los Angeles, Pacifica Radio's Women's Words, which is hosted by Los Angeles writer, Eloise Klein Healy. They discuss inspiration and reasoning for Rule's writing style, writing format, and characters, as well as Rule's involvement in arts communities. Rule also reads selections for her work. Rule(1931-2007) was a Canadian writer of lesbian-themed novels and non-fiction.
  - Alice Bloch and Aleida Rodriguez: Women Writers Series, 30 October 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 7)
    Alice Bloch and Aleida Rodriquez read selected written works for the Women Writers Series, organized by the Women's Building in Los Angeles, CA. Bloch is a Jewish lesbian writer, teacher, and has written two novels and an anthology of poetry. Born in Havana and brought to America at age nine, Rodríguez is a poet, essayist, and artist. Her poetry incorporates themes of exile, escape, and questions of impossible return.
  - Adrienne Rich: Interviewed by Eloise Klein Healy, 17 February 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 8)
    Recording of Adrienne Rich as guest on Eloise Klein Healy's radio show, Women's Words, on KPFK 90.7. They discuss Rich's decision to become a poet, her family and background, feminism, influences in her writing and her published works. Rich also reads selections from her work. Rich lived from 1929 to 2012 and was an American poet, essayist, and feminist.
  - Adrienne Rich: CSULB, 28 January 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 9-10)
    Recording of Adrienne Rich's reading performance at California State University Long Beach. The reading was organized by Department of Women's Studies. Rich reads a series of poems including, Power, Hunger, A Woman Dead in her Forties, Cost to Coast, Transit, For Julia in Nebraska, Rift, For Memory, Heroines, For Ethel Rosenberg, and The Spirit of Place. Rich lived from 1929 to 2012 and was an American poet, essayist, and feminist.
  - Adrienne Rich: Page 1 Books, 26 February 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 11)
    Adrienne Rich reads a Page 1 Bookstore. Rich begins her talk by championing women's and feminist bookstores. She also reads a variety of her poetry.
  - Ann Nietzke: Interviewed by Eloise Klein Healy, [ca. 1980s]; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 12)
    Ann Nietzke is a guest on Eloise Klein Healy's radio show, Women's Words, on KPFK 90.7. Ann Nietzke is a Los Angeles-based writer. The two writers discuss Nietzke's novel, Window Light, a fictional story based in Venice, CA. They also talk about Nietzke's background, career, and inspiration for writing.
  - Ann Nietzke: Literary Salon, 6 February 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 13)
    Ann Nietzke discusses her novel, Window Light, and reads excerpts from the book. The novel was written over three years and takes inspiration from the author's own observations from the Venice Beach Boardwalk.
  - Honor Moore: Women's Building, 1 April 1978; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 14)
    Honor Moore reads her poetry and other writing at the Women's Building in Los Angeles, CA. Moore is an American writer of poetry, creative nonfiction and plays. She is the author of three collections of poems: Red Shoes, Darling, and Memoir; two works of nonfiction, The White Blackbird and The Bishop's Daughter; and the play Mourning Pictures, which was produced on Broadway and published in The New Women's Theatre: Ten Plays by Contemporary American Women, which she edited.
  - Honor Moore: SPARC Reading, 29 July 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 15)
    Honor Moore's reading performance at the Social and Public Art Resource Center in Venice, CA. She reads select poems. Moore is an American writer of poetry, creative nonfiction and plays. She is the author of three collections of poems: Red Shoes, Darling, and Memoir; two works of nonfiction, The White Blackbird and The Bishop's Daughter; and the play Mourning Pictures, which was produced on Broadway and published in The New Women's Theatre: Ten Plays by Contemporary American Women, which she edited.
  - Eloise Klein Healy: Some From Ten Poems 1975-1985, audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 16)
    Recording of poems by Eloise Klein Healy. The poems were written between 1975 and 1985. Recording was done at Prism Productions in Sylmar, California. Healy is an American poet who has published 5 books of poetry and founded Arktoi Books.
    Duplicate recording in Poetry Cassettes Collection.
  - Hun, Moore, and Wright: Southern Women Writers, [ca. 1980s]; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 17)
    Nan Hunt, Louise Moore, and Judith Wright read their poetry.
  - Eloise Klein Healy: Poets in Los Angeles, 1 October 1986; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 18)
    Recording of KCRW 89.9 FM radio show, Poets in LA, with host Bill Mohr. Los Angeles poets, Jerome Rothenberg and Eloise Klein Healy are guests. Healy is an American poet who has published 5 books of poetry and founded Arktoi Books. Healy was also involved in the Woman's Building, the Westcoast feminist cultural center, throughout the 1970s and 1980s in various positions including teacher and Board of Directors. Healy was the Founding Chair of the MFA in Creative Writing Program at Antioch University Los Angeles, was the director of the Women's Studies Program at California State University Northridge, and was co-founder of ECO-ARTS, an eco-tourism/arts venture.
  - Judy Grahn: Sisterhood Bookstore, 31 January 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 19)
    Judy Grahn reads selections from her book. Paula Gunn Allen also reads at the event. Grahn is an American poet and writer. Her work focuses on feminist and lesbian issues. Grahn has written and published in 12 books. Grahn was a member of the Gay Women's Liberation Group, the first lesbian-feminist collective on the West Coast, founded in 1969.
- Black Women Anti Racism Cassettes, 1981-1989; Series 5.; 7 audio cassette tapes
  Stories, panels and discussions on the overlap between african american and jewish feminist politics.
  - no22 Forum Panel Tape 1 Sistervisions: Black Women Artists on Film Introduction by B. Love, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 1)
    panel at women's building on african american filmmakers including Betsy Smith (St. Louis Blues), Loraine Hansberry (Black Experience and the Creation of Drama) and Sharon Tate.
  - no11 Autobiography Invisible Minorities, 1981; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 2)
    bad recording
  - Anti Racism workshop, 13 June 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 3-4)
    Talk on Native American Lesbian issues and the need to research their history. Tape one features Terry Wolverton speaking on how to deal with racism as a writer. Tape two features a discussion on native american lesbian history.
  - women and the arts--UWEX Panel on Minority Women, 1985; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 5)
    Panelists discuss black women artists
  - The State of the Lesbian in the 80s Phyllis Lyon Del Martin, 1980s; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 6)
    Discussion on the political and everyday issues confronting lesbians in the 1980s
  - Young Lesbians and Black Lesbian Community, 8 October 1989, 10 December 1989; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 7)
    side one features a program of speaking out (by B. Love) focused on young lesbians.
    Side 2 features a KPFK Radio show on Black Lesbians including Jewel WIlliams
- Index to Records/Cassettes/Videos Cassettes, 1972-1982; Series 20.; 21 audio cassette tapes
  Recordings of various lectures, meetings, interviews, and readings on a number of topics, including literature, poetry, sexuality, feminism throughout history, lesbians in history, and child advocacy. Speakers include Serena Stier, Sharon McDonald, Mary Daly, John Bowell, Kate Millett, Elena Dikewomon, Dr. Ann Matter, Dr. Bernadette Brooten, Judy Grahn, and others.
  - Sharon McDonald at Whitman-Brooks, 2 May 1987; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 1)
    Sharon McDonald speaking at an event for Whitman-Brooks. She discusses her childhood and personal background, her experience coming out, education, scholarship, and work.
  - Ralph Macgowan: Coming Out in 1972, 1963, and 1984, 1 March 1985; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 2)
    Lindel MacGowan interview recorded for a class called Lesbian Lives, Lesbian Thought. Conversation is between two women, and they discuss their experience coming out because of a greater understanding of homo-sexuality. They also discuss their early lives, involvement in social and community activism, and personal relationships.
  - Nora Ortiz, 31 July 1973; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 3)
    Appears to be an interview or conversation between multiple women.
    Recording is only slightly audible. Audio on Side 1 only.
  - Mary Daly: At UCLA, 19 November 1987; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 4)
    Recording from KPFK's "Feminist Magazine," Mary Daly speaks at the University of California, Los Angeles, presenting an explanation of feminist theology. Daly was an American radical feminist philosopher, academic, and theologian. Daly, who described herself as a "radical lesbian feminist," taught at Boston College for 33 years. Daly retired in 1999, after violating university policy by refusing to allow male students in her advanced women's studies classes. She passed away in January 2010.
  - Lesbian Masquerade, 24 November 1979; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 5)
    Narrated by Lynn Fonfa, "Lesbian Masquerade" was a presentation of a slide show of a group of women in 19th century San Francisco who dressed as and passed as men. The San Francisco Lesbian History Project hosted the event, which took place in Los Angeles, CA.
  - Kate Millett: National Women's Political Caucus State Meeting, May 1972; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 6)
    The National Women's Political Caucus of California held a statewide organizing convention in Bakersfield. The recording is of guest speaker, Kate Millett addressing the convention audience. Millett discusses the state of the country as concerned with politics, women, and the women's liberation movement. She also addresses prevalent issues of the time, including upcoming elections, President Richard Nixon, and the Vietnam War. Kate Millet is an American writer, feminist, artist and a civil rights and peace activist. She is the author of the 1970 bestseller, "Sexual Politics."
    Audio breaks up throughout.
  - Karlene and Norma, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 7)
    Tape is broken.
  - John Boswell: Love in the Christian Tradition, 22 October 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 8)
    John Boswell presents his work and ideas on the issues surrounding sexuality, homosexuality, and the Christian tradition. The focus of the talk is on the Biblical story of Paul. Boswell was a prominent historian and a professor at Yale University. Many of Boswell's studies focused on the issue of homosexuality and religion, specifically homosexuality and Christianity.Boswell died of complications from AIDS in New Haven, Connecticut, on December 24, 1994, at age 47.
  - John Boswell: Evening Session, 22 October 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 9)
    John Boswell presents his work and ideas on the issues surrounding sexuality, homosexuality, and the Christian tradition. Boswell was a prominent historian and a professor at Yale University. Many of Boswell's studies focused on the issue of homosexuality and religion, specifically homosexuality and Christianity.Boswell died of complications from AIDS in New Haven, Connecticut, on December 24, 1994, at age 47.
  - Emily Culpepper: Feminist Authority on Scholarship, Does it Exist?, 11 March 1981; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 10)
  - Dr. Ann Matter and Dr. Bernadette Brooten: The Lazarus Project, 30 November 1985; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 11)
    Dr. Ann Matter presents an inquiry into the history of lesbians in medieval Europe. Dr. E Ann Matter is a Professor of Religious Studies at the University of Pennsylvania. Dr. Bernadetter J. Brooten presents an examination of biblical references to homosexuality, with a focus on Paul's condemnation of female homoeroticism. Brooten is an American religious scholar and Kraft-Hiatt Professor of Christian Studies at Brandeis University.
    Tape is inaudible at various points.
  - Elana Dykewomon: Benefit for Lesbian Cultural Center, 8 May 1981; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 12)
    Elana Dykewomon gives a poetry reading at a benefit for the Lesbian Cultural Center. It is unclear where the Center is located. Dykewomon is a Jewish lesbian activist, award-winning author, editor and teacher.
  - Judy Grahn Lecture: To Surface with Lesbian Gods, 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 13)
    Recording of Judy Grahn speaking as part of the Sappho Lectures at the New School. She presents the essay: "To Surface with Lesbian Gods." The lecture examines the gay elements in poetry throughout history, presents the work of lesbian poets, and discusses the significance of the ancient Greek lyric poet, Sappho. Grahn discusses her life and work as a writer. Judy Rae Grahn is an American poet, born July 28, 1940 in Chicago, Illinois. Grahn's work focuses on the feminist and lesbian experience.
  - Mary Garner: About Greenham, 22 November 1984; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 14)
  - San Francisco Gay and Lesbian History Project: Capitalism and Gay Identity, 13 April 1980; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 15)
    Recording of talk and open forum on the topic of why gay and lesbian communities have developed in specific areas, hosted by the San Francisco Gay and Lesbian History Project. The speakers are John D'Emilio, whose studies focused on the origins of the gay political movement, and Amber Hollibaugh, who participated in political activism for gay rights, worked Modern Times Bookstore and studied gender and sexuality. D'Emilio's talk, "Capitalism and Gay Identity," focuses on how capitalism-as an expanding, free labor system-has encouraged gay communities to build and become open, as well as shaped gay identity. The SF Gay and Lesbian History Project began in the fall of 1978 to discuss the history of gay and lesbian communities in San Francisco, as well as the rest of the country. The group conducts research and oral histories, as well as produces scholarly work and forums.
  - San Francisco Gay and Lesbian History Project: From Sexual Politics to Community, 13 April 1980; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 16)
    Recording of talk and open forum on the topic of why gay and lesbian communities have developed in specific areas, hosted by the San Francisco Gay and Lesbian History Project. The speakers are John D'Emilio, whose studies focused on the origins of the gay political movement, and Amber Hollibaugh, who participated in political activism for gay rights, worked Modern Times Bookstore and studied gender and sexuality. Hollibaugh's talk, "From Sexual Politics to Community," examines the roots of activism in gay and lesbian communities. The SF Gay and Lesbian History Project began in the fall of 1978 to discuss the history of gay and lesbian communities in San Francisco, as well as the rest of the country. The group conducts research and oral histories, as well as produces scholarly work and forums.
  - Lisa Ben Tape, [ca. 1980s]; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 17-18)
    Side 1: Recording of Lisa Ben discussing her writing and songwriting as a reflection of society and her personal life. She also performs her songs. Side 2: Ben discusses her views and attitudes towards society and gay culture. Lisa Ben was born Edith Eyde in San Francisco, CA. She is an editor, author, and songwriter. She created the first widely known lesbian publication, Vice Versa.
  - Del Martin, Phyllis Lyon, and Velnicia Rose, [ca. 1980s]; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 19)
    Interview with Del Martin and Phyllis Lyon. The couple discuss their personal experience coming out and seeking support, their relationship, their involvement is civil and feminist activism, as well the founding of the Daughters of Bilitis. 17 minutes of audio on Side 1 only.
  - Beverly Shaw, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 20)
    Short recording of Beverly Shaw. Beverly Shaw was a Los Angeles nightclub singer throughout the 1950s. Five minutes of audio on Side 1 only.
  - Serena Stier: Child Advocacy, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 4, Item 21)
    Discussion with Serena Stier on the topic of child advocacy, including issues with foster children, children's legal rights, and society's responsibilities to children. Stier has earned various degrees in psychology and has taught as a faculty member at the University of Iowa College of Law. She has published in the areas of legal ethics, child welfare, psychology, and public policy.
- Various Topics Cassettes, 1976-1994; Series 12.; 40 audio cassette tapes
  Recordings of various talks, conferences, interviews, narratives, radio shows, and meetings. Topics ranging from lesbian activism, herstory, lesbian pulp, lesbian literature and poetry, music, ageism, masturbation, and parenting.
  - American Library Association Gay Task Force Panel on Gay/Lesbian Archives, 28 June 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 1)
    Recording of Gay Task Force Panel at ALA, focused on gay and lesbian archives. Speakers: Barbara Gihings, Judith Schwarz, Jim Kepner
    Audiotape becomes warped at times, and is hard to understand. Side 1 only, stops recording at 10:15 minutes.
  - Yer Girlfriend, L-Word Spoken Here, 1991; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 2)